

 \searrow

nisha_89mohan@yahoo.co.in



8754493665



Chennai



linkedin.com/in/mohannisha

SKILLS

Agile methodologies Scrum framework, Project management, Stakeholder & Risk management

Quality Assurance - Test Strategy & Planning, Test Design, Embedded Testing

Defect management tools – IBM ClearQuest

Test management tools
– ApTest Manager, JIRA,
Zephyr, TestRail

Continuous Improvement, Process automation, Excel Macros

Windows , Citrix & Cluster servers, MAC, Novell OES, UNIX & Linux, VMPlayer, Oracle VirtualBox

DOMAIN

HEALTHCARE

PRINTER / OEM

EMBEDDED TESTING

Nisha M

Manager

Manager with over 13 years of experience in embedded testing domain. Experience in managing resources in multiple projects across geo-locations. Self-starter with the ability to work in a fast-paced environment, accompanied by strong leadership skills. Keen towards innovation and operational efficiency, holding 1 patent

WORK EXPERIENCE

Manager

Amazon Development Centre (India) Private Limited

08/2022 - Present

Roles/Responsibilities

- Developed project plans, budgets and timelines for 3 products and tracked progress against KPIs and delivered on time with 100% quality
- Facilitated scrum ceremonies along with the scrum master and coached team members on Agile principles and practices.
- Collaborated with Product Owners to prioritize backlog and ensure alignment with business goals.
- Mentored peer managers on project management processes and methodologies, ensuring adherence to standards
- Established process to track open defects blocking the upcoming release, raising flag to product owners by creating JIRA dashboard for each program
- Applied lean management technique (DMAIC) on the existing process and removed non-value-added activities to reduce overall cycle time, resulting in \$18000 annual savings (2023).
- Responsible for performance management of associates across geo-locations at regular intervals. Performed SWOT analysis for each of the team member and assigned tailored goals adhering to the role guidelines. Mentored and coached them for their path forward
- Cross-trained associates within teams to reduce people dependency. Clarify queries for the team members, manage daily floor operations and prepare reports with KPI metrics for leadership program review
- Active contributor in employee engagement committee and owned 2 events for PwD (Person with Disability), leader panel discussion for Women's Day and 2 team building events

Senior Technical Lead

HCL Technologies ltd

04/2019 - 07/2022

Xerox Corporation

Roles/Responsibilities

- Handled multiple projects Responsible for test strategy, planning, estimation, test scenarios, test execution plans
- Responsible for defect management, status reporting and reviewing all test deliverables before they reach customer
- Interaction with multiple stakeholders IT operations, Tools team, Infra team, Inventory team to accomplish project needs
- Identified and managed project risks, including resource constraints, scope changes, and technical challenges
- Quality compliance ISO external audit; High maturity practices (CMMI L5) implementation & sustenance; CMMI 2.0 external audit
- Key role in identifying improvement opportunities and implementing them across competencies
- Proposed over 5 quality ideas to the customer. 1 patent granted (US11778112B2). 1 patent application filed (US20220398052A1)

Chennai

Chennai

WORK EXPERIENCE

Test Lead

HCL Technologies ltd

02/2014 - 03/2019

Xerox Corporation

Roles/Responsibilities:

- Lead a team of 20 members for testing print drivers on various operating systems and handheld devices. Responsible for Test plan preparation, Task assignation, Effort tracking, Bug review, Status Reporting
- Played key role in optimization initiatives to remove redundant testing across teams
- Implemented pairwise testing to provide optimal coverage on print driver features
- Effective test design proposed for productization testing
- Automated weekly defect trend report using macros and implemented across multiple projects
- Worked across multiple test environments Windows, MAC, LINUX (openSUSE, Ubuntu, Fedora, Solaris Intel), UNIX (IBM AIX, HPUX, Solaris SPARC)

Test Engineer

HCL Technologies ltd

08/2010 - 01/2014

Abbott healthcare Pvt Ltd

Roles/Responsibilities:

- Performed UAT, internationalization test and exploratory test
- Key contributor in identifying bugs early in Mac platform
- Test case creation. Contributed to test plan creation

ORGANIZATIONS

Amazon Development Centre (India) Private Limited (08/2022 - Present) Manager, Quality Services

HCL Technologies ltd (08/2010 - 07/2022)

Senior Technical Lead

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

1 patent granted (US11778112B2), 1 patent application filed (US20220398052A1) for Xerox Corporation

IKM certified - Project Management

Certified Project Quality Analyst, Defect Prevention Analyst and Configuration Controller

Represented HCL ERS in CMMI 2.0 external audit, qualified without any NC (2020)

Participated in ISO 9001:2015 recertification audit (2017)

HCL - 'O Infinity - Hall of Fame' member

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering - Electrical and Electronics Saranathan College of Engineering -77%

08/2006 - 05/2010

Chennai

Chennai